Luke Adams

Junior Developer

- ≥ 1xa207agmail.com
- ♥ Birmingham
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/luke-adamscodes/
- https://github.com/luke123adams
- ▶ Personal site

EDUCATION

University of Birmingham,

NON-DEGREE DIPLOMA

Sep 2012 - Jul 2015

- Studied a number of ancient societies with a focus on objective interpretation of source material
- Organised a study tour to Turkey to investigate cultural developments through changes in ancient burial practices

SKILLS

Technical Skills

JavaScript/HTML/CSS
React
Node/Express
React testing library
Github
AuthO
RESTful API
PostgreSQL
TypeScript
Tailwind CSS

Currently learning:

Python
Next.JS
React Redux
CI/CD pipelines

PROJECTS

Craft Coop

 Currently working on a project with a senior developer to migrate a commercial site over to a content management system called storyblok.

PROFILE

I'm a former civil servant with 5 years experience looking to make a career change into the tech industry.

I'm fast learner who а is fascinated by patterns and I have a curiositu natural about underlying systems that make the world work. I built my first computer when I was 18 and have been tweaking and tinkering with PCs ever since.

I began my development journey at the School of Code after being chosen from thousands of applicants based on my soft skills, background and enthusiasm for the industry. After completing the full-time bootcamp in March, I have continued working on projects using the tech stack learned on the course as well as learning new technologies and languages. The main project I'm currently working on is a website with tools to help people run tabletop games such as Dungeons and Dragons.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

School of Code,

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT STUDENT

Sep 2022 - Jan 2023 | Birmingham

- 16 week full stack web development course
- Emphasis on teamwork with regular hackathons designed to emulate working on real-world tech projects
- Use of agile methodology reflecting on and improving working methods through sprints/stand ups
- Worked in pairs which were rotated weekly demonstrating ability to quickly adapt to different communication/working styles

- Site uses next.js and tailwind CSS
- Independently rebuilt the blog section of the site which has been reviewed and merged into the live codebase

FoodMap

- Full stack application designed to help people with specific dietary requirements such as those following a FODMAP diet.
- Users can create an account and scan barcodes of products in our database. The app will tell them if they can eat it based on their personal requirements
- Used kanban board to manage workload Used
 Disney ideation process to develop the idea,
 low and high fidelity wireframes to design
 front end
- CI/CD pipeline to allow futher developments after deployment
- My main responsibilities were around the back end, creating and testing CRUD routes and ensuring the app was communicating with our database correctly

Utellum

- Social media/noticeboard app designed to help bootcamp students connect and collaborate with each other
- User strengths/weaknesses and availability are stored on a database and displayed on the user profile
- Used agile methodology to develop the idea, produced an MVP by mid week and then built additional features on top

Fantasy name Generator

- Ongoing personal project full stack React app that allows users to create random names generated from an SQL database
- Authentication module built from scratch, allows users to create a profile, save names they like and add futher descriptions to them
- App also contains a custom-built RPG dice rolling module that allows users to roll different types of dice and displays a history of previous dice rolls

HM Revenue and Customs, DEBT MANAGEMENT CONSULTANT

Aug 2017 - Jul 2022

- Telephone based role providing advice and negotiating outstanding debt recoveru
- Used active listening and communication skills to conduct difficult discussions with empathy and understanding
- Worked with a wide range of companies from small businesses to major organisations with large liabilities
- Comfortable working within strict compliance frameworks
- Produced and delivered training materials to new officers

Sitel.

CUSTOMER SERVICE ADVISOR

Jul 2015 - Aug 2017 | Birmingham

- Assisted customers with the Waitrose website, processing orders and providing technical support for website crashes, helping customers with IT knowledge.
- Used communication skills to resolve customer complaints

INTERESTS

Music

I discovered a love for music early in my life. I was a shy child and I found music was a great way to connect with others that didn't require a lot of communication skills. I learned guitar from age 8 and was part of a regional ensemble that performed at venues such as Symphony Hall.

Gamina

I've loved playing video games from a young age when my dad bought home a copy of DOOM for the Windows 95. I especially enjoy team-based competitive games as it is a fun way to socialise with friends across the country who I don't get to see in person very often.